A Guide to the Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. Records, 1969-1991: SC 0135
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. Records,
1969-1991
Special Collections, James Madison University
Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc.
SC 0135
.66 cubic feet; 2 boxes
The Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. Records, 1696-1991, consist of the two boxes of administrative records of the Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, one of the first day care facilities in the area.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
This collection was received as a gift from Elizabeth Ihle, President of the Board of Directors, in May 1991.
Administrative History
After several years of planning, the Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. opened in May 1971 at Asbury United Methodist Church in Harrisonburg, as a community effort to address a widely recognized community need. It was supported at first by donations from local organizations, then by United Way and federal funds, and operated centers in several localities. Parents were charged for day care according to their income. A Board of Directors, composed of members of the community, gave guidance in policy making and fund raising. By 1991, approximately 70 children were being cared for. A detailed history is included in the collection.
Scope and Content
This Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. Records, 1969-1991, consists of the two boxes of administrative files of the Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc., one of the first day care facilities in the area. Materials include a detailed history of the center, by-laws, meeting minutes, budget information, correspondence, memoranda, and newsletters.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged topically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc; Day care centers -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Day care centers -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Day care centers -- Administration; Child care services -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Child care services -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Poor children -- Care; Child development; Federal aid to day care centers
- History of the Harrisonburg-Rockingham County Child Day Care Centers, Inc. 1971-1991, by Florence N. Gregory, p. i-112, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- History, cont., p. 113-144 & enhancements, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Boards of Directors, 1991-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- By-Laws and Personnel Policies, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Budget, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Budget, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1987-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1971-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newsletter, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newsletter, 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)